Gottlieb, Delia Collection of Jacob Potofsky Memorabilia 6286 MB
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Delia Gottlieb Collection of Jacob Potofsky Memorabilia
1956-1986
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gottlieb, Delia
6286 MB
2.17 cubic feet
1.7 linear ft.
Memorabilia.
6663059
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 20, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 26, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Gottlieb, Delia; Potofsky, Jacob S. (Jacob Samuel), 1894-1979; Roslyn, L.F.; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; La Guardia Airport; Pan American Airways Corporation; Riverside Memorial Chapel, Inc.; Sidney Hillman Foundation
6663059
- New York Joint Board - Pendant (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jacob Potofsky - Passports and mini-portfolio (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Jacob Potofsky - Travel paperwork and information (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Jacob Potofsky Citizenship paperwork (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Menu from LaGuardia Airport, NY (1940) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Certificate of Appreciation to Jacob Potofsky from City of New York (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Registers from Jacob Potofsky's funeral (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Business cards, misc., articles (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sidney Hillman picture; 'Travel in Soviet Russia' - 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sidney Hillman Sketches (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Jacob Potofsky - Honorary Degree from Roosevelt Univ.; Recognition of work for higher min. wage; News clipping; War Emergency Service Badge (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Death Certificates for Simon Potofsky & Sara Potofsky - Correspondence - Certificate of Naturalization and Certificate of Citizenship for Jacob Potofsky (Box 1, Folder 12)
- State of the Union Address by Lyndon Johnson (1964) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Buttons, Pins, Coins, etc. -- Metropolitan Florida; AFL-CIO; City of Rochester; Dept. of Labor; etc. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  20 pieces
- AFL-CiO, ACWA, ILGWU - Badges (Box 2, Folder 2)
  6 pieces
- Inaugural Committee, AFL-CIO, NRA - Badges, pins, tie tacks (Box 2, Folder 3)
  8 pieces
- Money clip, Pins, Badges, name plate, Pen - Jewish Labor Congress, Congressional Medal of Honor, AFL, ACWA, etc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  5 pieces
- Gold and Bronze coins, Ash tray, Gold Key (Atlantic City) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  President of the United States, Harry S. Truman; American Jewish Tercentenary, 1654-1954; Si Vis Pacem Cole Iustitiam 1919-1969 (2); Princeton University Bicentennial 1746-1946; Cincuentenario 1903-1953; Philip Murray 1886-1952; Man's Opportunities and Responsibilities Under Freedom; Coin of Beit-Shean - Items placed on acid free foam in bottom of box
- Coin and Pin - Israel Government Coins and Medals Corporation (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Coins and Pendant - Unione Mondiale ORT, Congresso Perl; For Distinguished Service to Higher Education, Brandeis University to Jacob S. Potofsky; Greetings from Israel (Box 3, Folder 3)
  3 pieces
- Pieces of maroon colored cloth (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Coin - Presented to Mr. Jacob Potofsky on the Opening of the New York Branch, Bank Hapoalim, B.M., November 25, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  in a small wooden box
- Paper weight - Brandeis Centennial Year Sponsored by Brandeis University - Gold coin incased in plastic (Louis Dembitz Brandeis Centennial1956) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  In a black box
- Plaque - Presented to Jacob S. Potofsky, A Founder of the United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York on the occasion of UJA's 25th Anniversary, 1939-1963 -- 25 Years of Rescue and Rebuilding (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Mallet - New York City Central Labor Council Celebrating Jacob S. Potofsky - Week April 27 - May 2, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Mallet -- Presented by Southern Regional Joint Board to Jacob S. Potofsky General President ACWA May 28th, 1972, 28th Biennial Convention, Miami Beach, Florida (Box 3, Folder 9)
- American Labor Party, Primary Election. 1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- American Labor party. Primary Election. 1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Under Secretary of State. Luncheon Invitation, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Israel Ambassador. Breakfast Invitation, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- CIO 14th Constitutional Convention Program, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- News clipping. Esther Peterson. NY Times December 8, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Jacob Potofsky Passport (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Silver Jubilee Convention - ACWA - Program, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Wallet size photo of Jacob Potofsky (Box 4, Folder 9)
- News clippings (Box 4, Folder 10)
- News clippings (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Sketch (pencil) of Jacob Potofsky; 3-Cent Labor Day Commemorative U.S. Postage Stamp, issue 1956 (Box 4, Folder 12)